welcome to new every day this week we're
我们这周欢迎新的每一天
talking about seven traits of the holy
谈论神圣的七个特征
spirit but we're not going up covering
精神，但 我们不会 覆盖
all seven we're just doing the first one
所有七个我们只是做第一个
and we're going to be covering it from a
我们将从a覆盖它
devotional within the YouVersion Bible
YouVersion圣经中的虔诚
app where you're talking about it just a
应用程序，你在谈论它只是 一个
few minutes to grab this is new every
几分钟抢，这是每一个新
day with Jeff Weston Lawrence Cruz
与杰夫韦斯顿 劳伦斯克鲁兹的 一天
[Music]
[音乐]
welcome to new every day
欢迎新的每一天
I'm Jeff Wesson I'm Lawrence Cruz so
我是杰夫威森我是劳伦斯克鲁兹所以
glad to have you here with us if you're
很高兴你能 和 我们在一起， 如果你的话
just checking out a new every day for
只是每天检查一个新 的
the first time we are in our fourth
我们第一次进入第四次
season we've been doing this show for
我们一直 在做这个节目
quite a long while now and I think we've
很长一段时间，我 想我们已经
been on it now about three four months
一直在 它现在 大约三4个月
and every week we seem to be coming up
每个星期我们似乎 都要来了
with these great topics you just push
你推动 这些伟大的话题
the bar a little bit higher and this
酒吧高一点，这个
week we're gonna be taking it to the
这一周，我们将把它带到
next level we're talking about the Holy
下一级我们正在谈论神圣
Spirit oh that's a good subject it is
灵哦， 这是一个很好的主题 是
but for some people the whole idea of
但对于一些人来说，整个想法
the Holy Spirit is foreign to them
圣灵对他们来说是陌生的
because there are certain types of
因为有某些类型的
denominations that may not recognize the
可能无法识别的教派
Holy Spirit and so if you do come from
如果你来的话，圣灵等等
one of those denominations listen with
其中一个 教派 倾听
an open mind this is all biblical
一个开放的心态， 这一切都符合圣经
scripture based teaching and we might
基于经文的教学我们可能会
press you and challenge you a little bit
按下你并向你挑战一下
and if this is common to you then learn
如果这对你来说很常见， 那就学习吧
grow enjoy it absolutely we're gonna be
成长享受它绝对 我们会成为
unpacking some pretty big stuff that is
拆包一些相当大的东西 ， 是
life-changing
改变生活
certainly life-changing nothing in the
当然， 生活中没有任何改变
kingdom of God can ever happen without
上帝的国度永远不会发生
the person of the Holy Spirit at work so
工作中圣灵的人如此
it's true there are some people who
确实有一些人
perhaps would you know maybe not talk
也许你知道也许不会说话
about the Holy Spirit at all and yet I
关于圣灵，但我
think most of us I think we're gonna
想想我们大多数人，我 想我们会
find are just gonna identify with what
发现只是要 认同什么
the pages of the Bible teach us flat-out
圣经的页面教我们 平坦
about who this third person of the Holy
关于谁是第三人 的神圣
Trinity is right yeah the Holy Spirit
三位一体是正确的 是圣灵
and so I would agree that we were
所以我同意我们是
talking earlier Jeff that some people
早些时候说杰夫，有些人
are a little maybe spooked out about
有点可能被吓坏了
this Holy Spirit especially if they've
这圣灵特别是如果他们的话
heard another translation of the Bible
听过圣经的另一个翻译
refer to as the Holy Ghost
称为圣灵
not the Holy Ghost right I just imagine
我 想象的不是圣灵
putting myself into the shoes of someone
把自己放在 别人 的 鞋子里
who's never been inside a church and I'm
谁从来没有进 过 教堂，我也是
thrilled I meet people every day who
我很高兴我每天 都会见到谁
don't go to church and have no
不去教堂也没有
understanding whatsoever about what I
了解任何关于 我
believe is eternal life and my entire
相信是永生 和我的全部
like eternity rests in what I believe
像永恒掌握 在 我的信仰
here and they're loving great people who
在这里，他们 爱的是伟大的人
don't have any clue at all if I put my
如果我把 我的 话，根本没有任何线索
self in their shoes and talked about a
自言自语，谈到 了
ghost living inside of me that's
鬼魂生活在我的内心
something out of like Halloween yeah
像万圣节一样的东西是的
it's almost like my goodness where is it
这几乎就像我的善良在哪里
you said you go every Sunday morning and
你说你每个星期天早上都去
how many people are there right it's
有多少人是对的
that sort of thing and of course I mean
那种事 ，当然我的 意思
if we're in the church we hear about in
如果我们在教堂里听到的话
the name of the Father the Son and the
儿子和儿子的名字
Holy Spirit I mean what a beautiful
圣灵我的意思是多么 美丽
blessing it seems to be easy for us to
祝福它对我们来说似乎很容易
understand but who is the Holy Spirit
明白但谁是圣灵
right what a nature what does he do why
这是一个多么大自然他为什么做的事情
do we even talk about him why is he
我们甚至谈论他为什么是他
mentioned in the Bible we've got some
在圣经中提到我们有一些
great weeks ahead absolutely yeah we're
前几周绝对是的，我们是
going to be taking the next 7 weeks to
将 在未来7周内 完成
unpack this entire topic about the
解开关于这个的整个主题
characteristics of the Holy Spirit and
圣灵的特点 和
we're pulling it I mean there's always
我们拉它， 我的意思是永远
an element in just about any lesson of
几乎所有教训中的一个元素
the going oh I've heard that from
企业持续哦，我听说过，从
somewhere and maybe you've got the Bible
在某个地方，也许你已经得到了 圣经
app from you virgin and so we are
来自你 处女的 应用程序 ，所以我们是
actually pulling from one of those
实际上 从其中一个拉出来
devotionals right here cellphone that's
灵修在这里的手机 那是
right yeah it's called the seven rules
右没错这就是所谓的 七大规则
of the Holy Spirit
圣灵
it's a devotional from the you version
这是从 你的版本一个虔诚
up Jeff and I would love nothing more
杰夫和我不会再爱了
for you to go to the up and you can read
你可以 去 看看，你可以阅读
we make no apologies we're giving all
我们不会向所有人致歉
full credit to this app that's leading
完全归功于这个 领先的应用程序
us through the next seven weeks about
我们通过未来7周 约
understanding who the Holy Spirit is
了解圣灵是谁
what he does how we can get to know him
他怎么做 才能 认识 他
and we would encourage you to read along
我们鼓励 你一起阅读
with us and/or read ahead you can send
与 我们和/或 提前阅读，您可以发送
in your comments your questions maybe
在你的评论中你的问题可能
great ideas and all of the above
伟大的想法和以上所有
absolutely yeah so it's gonna be a great
绝对是的，所以这将是一个伟大的
seven weeks together I'm looking forward
七个星期在一起，我很期待
to it so maybe we can dive in you
它也许我们可以潜入你
absolute week number white one and the
绝对周数白色和
Holy Spirit is our regenerator now
圣灵现在是我们的再生者
here's what I'm gonna do I'm gonna start
这就是我要做的事，我要开始了
reading from the app and there's never
从 应用程序 读取 和从未有
any problem with us talking about it and
跟我们谈论 它和任何问题
again we welcome your thoughts in your
再次 ，我们欢迎您的 想法在 你的
comments but just meet the Holy Spirit
评论，但只是满足圣灵
okay welcome hi my name is Lawrence and
好的 欢迎我的名字是劳伦斯和
you are I wonder what his voice it sound
你是我想知道他的 声音是什么
like I think it's a stole yeah and oh
就像我认为这是 一个偷了呀哦
yeah still small voice yeah I believe
是的还是小声音，我相信
I've heard that voice meet the Holy
我听说那 声音符合圣洁
Spirit who can do it all okay even there
能够做到这一切的精神即使在那里也可以
stop right there
停在那儿
Jeff is this true like is the Holy
杰夫就像圣洁一样真实
Spirit someone who can do everything
精神可以做 任何事情的人
like is this what we're learning here
就像这是我们在这里学到的东西
yeah absolutely I mean that when you
是的，我的意思是，当 你
when you break down who the Holy Spirit
当你分解谁是圣灵
is he is part of the Trinity is that he
他是三位一体的一部分 就是他
is that third part of who God is you've
是上帝是你的第三部分
got God the Father God the Son being
得到了上帝，圣父是神的儿子
Jesus and the Holy Spirit and when you
耶稣和圣灵，当你
look at the chronology of the Bible it
看看圣经 它 的年表
was God first there then Jesus came and
是第一个上帝然后耶稣来了
then you've got the Holy Spirit who was
然后你就拥有了圣灵
came in after Jesus to be that guide for
在耶稣成为那个指南之后进来了
us and that's another topic we'll unpack
我们这是另一个我们要打开的话题
later but you know sometimes the best
以后 你知道有时候最好的
way I've heard the Holy Spirit described
这样 我听说描述圣灵
is your conscience mm you know that
是你的良心- 你知道，
little still small voice that speaks to
说话的小声音
you in those moments going should I be
你应该在那些时刻去做
doing that is there a better way around
这样做有更好的方法
than Wow
哇
yeah you're taking me back to Bible
是的，你带我回到圣经
College where we know in the last days
我们在最后几天知道的学院
which which are upon us
哪些是我们的
we know that biblically we're in the
我们知道圣经中我们在
last days even as far as the church
最后的日子 甚至 到了教堂
beginning and Christ going to heaven so
开始和基督如此去天堂
that's been a 2,000 year journey and
这是一个2000年的旅程和
many people I talked to seem to think
我交谈的很多人似乎都在思考
that the temperature in the world is
世界的温度是
eating up it's almost like I think we're
吃起来几乎 就像我认为 的 那样
hiding any time now I think so come to
现在隐藏任何时间，我想是 这样 来的
the table dinner is served and there's a
餐桌晚餐供应，有一个
marriage supper of the Lamb that could
羔羊的婚筵 可以
be happening sooner than later Wow what
哇早点发生什么哇
does all that mean I can only imagine an
这一切意味着我只能想象一个
unchurched person saying what are they
未受教育的人说什么是他们
but this this Holy Spirit is powerful
但是这个圣灵是 强大的
and yeah he can do anything and he's
是的，他可以做任何事， 他是
referred to some people believe as the
提到有些人认为是
restraining influence no it doesn't say
限制影响 不，它 不说
that yeah there is a restraining
是的，有一种限制
influence that that you know if God
影响你知道如果上帝
didn't have this restraining influence
没有这种限制性的影响
on earth right now pardon the expression
现在在地球上原谅这个表达
but all hell would break loose in a way
但是一切都会在某种程度上破裂
like we've never yet seen sure
就像我们从未见过的那样
absolutely and I believe it's this same
绝对，我相信它也是如此
Holy Spirit who is even powerful enough
圣灵甚至足够强大
to say hey you know evil I know you're
说嘿，你 知道邪恶， 我知道你是
you're willing to do a bad job here and
你愿意在 这里 做坏事
make things horrible but enough yeah I'm
让事情变得可怕，但是，我是
just gonna stop you right there
就这样会阻止 你
and that's the kind of power we're
这就是我们的力量
talking about in this person called the
在这个人谈论称为
Holy Spirit which i think is from a
我认为圣灵 来自一个
human perspective that's hard to wrap
人类的观点很难包装
your mind around because yeah we see the
你的思绪因为我们 看到了
world and the physical we see it in the
世界， 我们看到它的 物理
day to day tangible life that we have
我们拥有的日常有形生活
and to imagine that there's an entire
并想象 有一个完整的
spiritual world going on around us where
精神世界在我们周围继续前进
there is those daily battles and the
有那些日常战斗和
Holy Spirit is the one you know keeping
圣灵是 你知道 保持 一个
it at bay gives a very different focus
它在海湾 提供了一个非常不同的焦点
on how you go about your day like yeah
关于你如何去做你的一天，就像是的
there's a lot happening around me that I
还有很多我， 我 身边发生的事情
can't see and I may not even understand
看不到，我甚至可能都不明白
mm-hmm but it's happening it isn't there
mm-hmm但它正在发生 它不存在
you know I think of you know one of the
你知道我在想你知道的一个
bands I was listening to as a young
乐队我小时候都在听
teenager was DC Talk and they had a yo
少年是DC Talk，他们有一个哟
one of their songs and I don't remember
他们的一首歌我不记得了
what it is there was a clip from
那里有 一个剪辑
somebody speaking that talks about the
有人在 谈论这个问题
Holy Spirit and and and he says it's
圣灵和他和他说这是
he's like the wind you can't see the
他就像你看不到的风
wind but you can feel the effects of the
风，但你可以感受到的影响
wind yeah and the Holy Spirit is very
风呀，圣灵非常
much the same way yeah in the spiritual
耶和华在灵性上是一样的
realm and there's times where he's
境界，有时候他在哪里
working his deal yeah and we can feel
他的 工作 合同是的，我们能感觉到
things happening out of it oh he's
事情发生在 它 外面 哦，他是
working as deal and we can feel there's
作为交易工作，我们可以感受到
something going on
发生了什么事
so this Holy Spirit God yeah who we
所以这个圣灵上帝是的我们是谁
Revere who we are seeking to honor
我们正在寻求尊重的里维尔
especially in these next seven episodes
特别是 在 接下来的七集中
he has limitless power we believe that
他有 我们相信 无限的权力
he's the one who was there at the
他是一个谁 在那里的
beginning brooding over the earth
开始在地球上沉思
hovering over the waters that's a at the
徘徊在水面上
birth of everything that we know Terra
我们所知道Terra的一切都诞生了
Firma he's this restraining influence at
Firma他是这种克制的影响力
the end of all time he's the God with
有史以来他一直都是上帝
limitless power I love this Jeff who's
无限的力量我爱这个杰夫是谁
willing to come and live inside of frail
愿意 来到体弱的生活
human me right how amazing how wonderful
人类我是多么奇妙多么美妙
is the songwriter said right how
这位词曲作者是怎么说的
marvelous
奇妙
Oh is this God who comes to live with us
噢 ，这位来与我们同住的上帝
and that is such an interesting thing to
那就是这样一个有趣的事情
think about when you think that the Holy
想想当你 认为神圣的时候
Spirit who is all-powerful can do all
的精神， 谁是 全能的可以做所有
things
事
dwell within us is part of who we are
在我们住的是我们是谁的一部分
it's it's that that fiber of our
它就是我们的纤维
spiritual living mm-hmm and to think
精神生活mm-hmm 并思考
that we are capable of tapping into that
我们 有能力 利用 它
power to change the way our lives go now
改变现在生活方式的力量
that doesn't mean I want to win a
这并不 意味着我想赢得一场比赛
million dollars and then chi-ching you
百万美元，然后给你充气
get the winning lottery ticket it's not
获得中奖彩票 不是
what I mean by changing but it's it's
我的意思是改变，但它就是它
the way that we live our lives it's the
那我们 的生活 的 方式， 它是将
challenges that we face and how we
我们面临的挑战，以及 我们如何
respond that that's when you really get
回答那是你真正得到的
to see the power of the Holy Spirit kick
看到 圣灵 的 力量踢
in when we listen to that leading within
在当我们听 的是领先的 内
our life just the confidence excuse me
我的生活只是 对我的信心
the confidence that that that rises up
这是该上升的信心
in me as we just as I with you real time
在我身边，就像我和你一样 真实
consider that this powerful God lives in
认为这位强大的上帝住在里面
us he lives in me and I mean it's like
我们他住在我身边， 我的意思就是 这样
yeah right
是的，没错
so of course I can do all things right
所以当然我可以做正确的事
your Bible verse through Christ who
通过基督你的圣经经文
gives me strength yeah like there's I
给我 力量， 是的， 就像我一样
can do all
可以做到
things through God right Father the Son
通过上帝的事就是 圣父
the Holy Spirit allowing us what an
圣灵允许我们做什么
incredible reality that such a powerful
令人难以置信的现实，如此强大
God is willing to take up residence to
上帝愿意 居住
live inside of me but Paul the Apostle
住在我里面， 但使徒保罗
says hey don't you know that you that's
说哎你不知道 你 这是
your I hate all of us you are a temple
你恨我们所有人你是一个神庙
of the Holy Ghost what he resides within
他居住在 圣灵 里面
those who say God please come into my
那些谁 说上帝，请进入我的
life right and that a lot of that is
生活权利，其中很多 是
because of the change that came through
因为经历 的 变化
Christ
基督
prior to Christ there was the tabernacle
在基督之前有会幕
where the Spirit of God resolved resided
神的灵解决了
right Christ came changed that know no
正确的基督改变了，不 知道
longer a need for the tabernacle and
对帐幕的需求越来越长
because of accepting Christ we now have
因为接受我们现在的基督
that holy spirit within us guiding us
我们内在的圣灵引导着我们
being a part of who we are yeah we do he
作为我们是谁的一部分是的，我们做 他
writes on our hearts how would all what
写在我们的 心 怎么 会所有什么
is that all about how about you artisans
是所有 关于 你 怎么样 工匠
well there's doctor God at work our
好吧， 医生上帝在工作 我们
artist God at work just writing his name
艺术家上帝在工作时只是 写下他的名字
on our hearts and blood oh and our our
在我们的心和血哦和我们的
name he cherishes us it's so good oh my
他珍惜我们的名字， 这太好了哦
goodness
善良
see this is what this is this is the
看看这是什么，这是这是
reality of what this powerful God is
这个 强大的上帝是 什么的现实
able to come and live inside of me but
能够过来住在 我的 内心 但是
Jeff there's a huge problem on my own
杰夫，我自己有一个很大的问题
without Christ I am filled with rotten
没有基督， 我就 充满了 腐烂
sin right in fact I can clean up good I
罪吧？ 其实我可以收拾好我
can mind my manners I can watch my mouth
可以放心我的举止， 我可以看到我的嘴
and speak properly but all of those good
说 得好但所有这些都好
works if you will do nothing to take
如果你不采取任何行动，那就有效
away how polluted my sinful nature is no
离开我的罪恶本性是如何污染的
matter what that's right
重要的是什么
but this incredible God says he's
但这个令人难以置信的上帝说他是
willing to come in and
愿意 进来
citing me so it's like we've got this
引用我的话 就像我们有这个
perfect storm right this holy God so
完美风暴对这神圣的 神 如此
perfect and without sin coming to live
完美 而没有 罪来生活
inside of me I mean what is that all
在我内心，我的意思 是 这一切
about except that he does a powerful
除了他做了一个强大的
work to change me from the inside out
努力从内到外改变我
that's right
这是 正确的
oh now we've got to take a quick break
哦， 现在我们得快点 休息一下
but we're going to continue to have this
但我们将 继续这样做
conversation and dive into that point
谈话并深入探讨 这一点
with that the theme of the Holy Spirit
与圣灵 的主题
is our regenerator I can't wait
是我们的再生者， 我等不及了
don't go anywhere stick around for more
不要去任何地方坚持更多
from new every day for a limited time
来自 新的每一天有限的时间
get your hands on limited-edition shirts
获得限量版的衬衫 你的 手
from the category 5 TV network these
来自5 类 电视网这些
high quality shirts are manufactured by
高品质的衬衫是由
teespring a fundraising website and your
teespring筹款网站和你的
purchase will help support the shows we
购买将有助于支持我们的节目
produce get yours today and send us your
今天生产你的产品并发送给我们
pictures to be featured on the
图片将在上面展出
corresponding show visit cap v dot TV
相应的节目访问上限v点 电视
slash shirts to support us and get your
削减衬衫， 以支持我们 ，让你的
official Network shirt today cat5 dot TV
官方网络衬衫今天cat5点 电视
slash shirts
斜衬衫
[Music]
[音乐]
welcome back to new every day if you're
如果你是的话，欢迎每天回到新的一天
just joining us we are talking about the
刚加入我们，我们正在 谈论的
holy spirit and we are breaking down the
圣灵 ，我们正在打破
seven traits of the Holy Spirit which
圣灵的七个特征
comes from a devotional within the
来自内心的虔诚
YouVersion Bible app so if you have that
YouVersion圣经应用程序，如果你有
app by all means look up the devotional
app一定要查看灵修
the the topic we're covering this week
我们本周讨论的话题
is the Holy Spirit is our regenerator
是圣灵 是我们的再生者
and just before the break you were
就在 你休息 之前
talking about how without the Holy
谈论如何没有圣洁
Spirit the core of who we are is rotten
精神是 我们 的核心 是腐烂的
it's that sinful nature yeah and that's
这是罪恶的本性， 是的，那就是
kind of where we took a break so let's
样 的，我们休息了一下，让我们
pick off there yeah actually thank you
选择那里， 实际上谢谢你
yeah it's true it's wow I mean the Bible
是的，这是真的， 哇，我的意思是圣经
is very clear as says in Romans that all
正如罗马人所说的那样，非常清楚
of us have sinned and I've never had one
我们有罪， 我从来没有过
authentic conversation with anybody who
与任何人进行真实的对话
ever denied that anyway I think most
无论如何我总是否认这一点
people are pretty willing you know some
人们非常愿意你了解一些
people even pretty proud of it you know
你知道，人们甚至为此感到自豪
how it is true but at any rate so and
如何这是真的，但无论如何 左右 ，
it's not just our actions are sinful but
这不仅仅是我们的行为是罪恶的
again but our very nature is sinful
再次，但我们的 本性是有罪的
and the wonderful good news is is that
和美妙的好消息是，是 ，
God says I don't want anybody to have to
上帝说我不 希望任何人必须这样做
stay that way
保持 这种方式
and so Holy Spirit gets involved and as
所以圣灵会参与其中
Jeff had mentioned in the seven roles of
杰夫曾在 七个角色 提及
the Holy Spirit we're we want to somehow
圣灵 我们想要以 某种方式
say today that hit one of his roles is
今天说他的一个角色是
that he's a regenerator he's the one who
他是一个再生者，他就是那个人
brings here as new life and Jeff all of
带来了新生活 和杰夫的全部
this these are my words about me all of
这些是我对我的所有话语
the pollution inside of Who I am as a
我作为一个人的污染
person who is sinful to the core
对核心 有罪的人
independent of how my actions and how
独立于我的行为和 方式
nice and kind I may choose to be like my
善良善良我可能会选择像我一样
nature is still prone to just wander
大自然仍然容易徘徊
away from God and say no hit the road I
远离上帝 ，说 没有打 我的路
don't need you independent god buzz off
不需要你独立的 神嗡嗡声
I'll do this on my own forget God I'll
我会自己忘记 上帝，我 会这样做
be my own boss and with all that
做我自己的老板和所有这些
pollution he's still Holy Spirit comes
污染他仍然是圣灵来的
and says you know what I don't want to
并说你知道我不 想要的
leave you that way I want to come in but
离开你那样我想进来但是
in order for me to come in and live
为了让 我进来 住
inside of you like I said I would I have
在你里面，我说 我 会拥有
to do something and that is I have to
做某事，这是我必须 做的
regenerate you Lawrence what and he
再生你劳伦斯和他一起
comes in Jeff the role of the Spirit is
来自杰夫，精神的角色是
that he comes in the Bible says and he
他在圣经中说和他说
makes us brand new what it's like like I
让我们像我一样 崭新的品牌
never ever ever had ever sin again in my
永远不曾 在再犯罪了我
life what that's one of the roles of the
生活是什么，是谁的角色 之一
Holy Spirit
神圣的灵魂
you can tell I'm excited about who he is
你可以说我很高兴自己是谁
in our lives there's a whole lot of Hope
在我们的生活中， 有很多 希望
in that state oh isn't there the regret
在那种 状态哦，不是有遗憾
that is removed because of that knowing
这是因为 ， 知道 的去除
that we are made new is absolutely free
我们 是新的是完全免费的
and so many people need that mm there we
那么多人需要那个我们
are we live in a fallen world and when
我们生活在一个堕落的 世界 吗？
people don't have the Holy Spirit as a
人没有圣灵 作为
part of who they are
他们是 谁的一部分
mm then you don't feel that release from
mm然后你不觉得释放
the regret you don't feel that renewing
遗憾的是你没有感觉到更新
that comes with that
附带说
and it's hard to explain the emotion
并且很难 解释这种情绪
that comes with that Redemption but the
随着救赎 而来 ，但是
best way I can think of would be
我能 想到的 最佳方式
describe
描述
you're sitting there in the you know the
你坐在那里，你知道 的
chamber about to be given the death
即将给出的死亡室
penalty and somebody goes it's done your
罚款，有人去做你的
crime is wiped out like the relief you
犯罪就像你的救济一样 消失了
could feel and that is on a daily basis
可以感受到，这是每天
what we can experience with the Holy
我们可以用 神圣的 经验
Spirit through that regeneration yeah
精神 通过再生耶
this isn't grown okay now I'm going I'll
这是不行的 成长，现在我要去 我会
tell you whether there's a few things I
告诉你我是否有一些事情
want to say too interestingly enough my
我 想说的 太有趣了
own brother when he was I was 17 no I
我17岁时自己的兄弟不是我
was 15 he was 17 we were at a party one
15 岁那年他 才17岁 参加派对
time with the youth group and you know
与 青年团体的 时间， 你知道
how that goes we were going to church
怎么回事我们去教堂
hey this nice family invites everybody
嘿这个好家庭邀请所有人
back to the house and they just put on a
回到房子，他们只是穿上了
spread it's like everybody's racing to
传播它就像每个人都在竞争
get there because they want the best
到那里因为他们想要最好的
food and there's plenty for everybody
食品和有很多 为 大家
but you're young and you know you're
但 你很年轻，你 知道你
just got to eat right there first we get
刚吃 在那里首先我们得到
to this party and one girl shows up with
这个党和一个女孩显示了
a set of keys because she's won an award
一套钥匙，因为 她赢得了一个奖项
for the weekend she's been so good
周末她一直很好
underwear
内衣
that the boss says hey way to go I
老板的路要走， 我说哎
rented you a Corvette for the weekend oh
周末租了一辆Corvette 哦
okay
好的
so this young girl who maybe is 19 or 20
所以这个年轻女孩可能是19岁或20岁
has the keys to a brand-new Corvette and
有一把全新的Corvette和
shows up and says to the youth group hey
出现并对青年团体说嘿
anybody want to take the car for a spin
任何人都想把车开走
oh no so my brother among many others
哦，不 ，我的兄弟和 其他许多人一样
says I do I even said I do but I didn't
说我做我甚至说我做，但我没有
have my license so I said well maybe
有我的执照，所以我 也许 说得好
then they uh anyway so we crammed into
然后他们呃所以我们 挤进去了
this car it's a Corvette there's four of
这辆车是Corvette 的四个
us crammed in a Corvette in a two-seater
我们穿着双座的Corvette挤满了人
I'm in the back window with my friend
我跟朋友在后窗
and my brother is booking it around
而我的兄弟正在预订
while I guess what he's going a little
虽然我猜他会走多远
faster and a little faster and a little
更快，快一点和 一点
faster and I mean there is a law called
更快，我的意思是有 一个法律
gravity and you might think that in a
重力，你可能会认为在一个
Corvette you can defy it but you can't
克尔维特你可以挑战它，但你不能
long story short he wiped out we wiped
长话短说他消灭 了 我们擦了擦
out we spun oh through lawn after lawn
我们在草坪后穿过草坪
after um crash right in to a tree and
在你撞到 一棵树后崩溃 了
and I mean there's just red coming down
而我的意思是只有红色下降
our faces you know cuts and bruises
我们的面孔你 知道削减和瘀伤
thank God everybody walked away with
感谢上帝，每个人都带走了
just very very minor physical you know
只是非常 非常轻微的身体，你知道
hurt but a lot of like oh no panic and
伤害但很多 像哦没有恐慌和
like what's gonna happen right yeah okay
喜欢会发生什么事就没关系，好​​吧
here's the point of all this story the
这是所有这个故事的重点
irony is that my brother he rightfully
具有讽刺意味的是我的兄弟他是 理所当然的
got charged and they were going to lay
被指控，他们打算躺下
on a criminal charge and they were in
在刑事指控和 他们在
Canada here and they reduced it to one
加拿大在这里，他们减少到一个
that was non criminal but the highest
这不是 犯罪，但最高
they could give him before it would be a
他们可以在它成为之前给他
criminal charge and he got charged he
刑事指控 和他指控 他
lost his license for a period of time he
失去了他的执照了 一段时间，他
was filled with remorse and he changed
充满了 懊悔， 他改变了
his ways because of it so he was 17 and
因为这样他的方式所以他17岁
in about three years later he wanted to
在 大约三年 后，他想
become a police officer okay and because
成为一名警察 好吧 ，因为
he had this on his record he wasn't
他记录下他没有
allowed to even apply right yes okay
甚至可以申请，是的
okay so you understand that now that's
好的，所以你明白， 现在 就是这样
where I'm going with this
在那里我有 这个打算
why for pardon he went and applied for
为什么要原谅他去申请
what is called a pardon the long story
所谓赦免长篇故事
short is they said sir we've seen you we
总之就是他们说，主席先生，我们已经看到了你 ，我们
recognize or there at least we're gonna
认识到或 至少我们会
trust that this was a one-off and it's
相信这是一次性的， 而且是
not really who you are
不是真的你是谁
we'd like to give you this pardon which
我们想给你这个赦免 其
is just like the accident never happened
就像事故从未发生过一样
he applied to the police force and he's
他向 警察局 申请 了他
ready to retire any day 30 years later
30年后的 任何一天都准备退休
Wow
哇
Jeff this is what God the regenerator
杰夫这是上帝的再生者
what the role of the Holy Spirit is that
圣灵的作用是 什么
he so rightly said it he comes into our
他如此正确地说他进入我们的行列
lives he says yeah hey I know you wiped
生活他说是的嘿我知道你 擦了
out in a car
在车里
I know Lawrence you did this and you
我知道劳伦斯，你这样做了
don't want anybody to know about it and
不希望 任何人知道 它和
I'm not gonna tell anybody but I know
我不会告诉任何人，但我知道
says the Lord and how many how long is
耶和华说， 有多长时间
the list of sins we could say I know
我知道的罪孽清单
you've done it but here's what I'm gonna
你已经完成了，但这就是我 要做的
do I'm gonna write you a pardon just as
我会 像 你一样 给 你 原谅
though you had never sinned now how does
虽然你现在从未犯过罪，但是怎么办
that truth make us feel oh like cloud
那个真理让我们感觉 像云一样
nine cloud nine it's incredible it's a
九 云九令人难以置信它是一个
role of God in the person of the Holy
上帝的 神圣 的人 作用
Spirit who longs to come in to your life
渴望 进入你 生活的精神
as he has come into ours and to make you
因为他进入 我们的并且 为了你
brand new as though you'd never had the
全新的，好像你从来没有过
accident I mean as though you've never
意外，我的意思是 ，好像你从来没有
ever ever sinned and he regenerates
从来没有犯过罪，他重生了
that's one of the chief roles of the
这是该主要角色之一
Holy Spirit and because of that then he
圣灵成 ， 因为 后来他
says holy God comes and lives within us
说圣洁的神来到我们里面
this powerful all-knowing God comes and
这个强大的无所不知的上帝来了
lives inside of you and me look it's
生活在你的内心，我 看着它
awesome it is I'm sitting I say now how
真棒，我 坐着， 我现在怎么说
do you talk about you can't know it's
你说的是 你不 知道的 吗？
good news man we say thank you Lord yes
好消息的人，我们说声谢谢 上帝 是
we'd say thank you Lord and it was John
我们说谢谢主，这是约翰
chapter 3 verse 5 and Jesus said to this
第3章第5节耶稣对此说
man named
男人的名字
adems he was a leader and he was
阿德玛斯他是一名领导者而且他 是
curious how can one get into the kingdom
好奇怎么能进入王国
of God like I'm like I like who you are
上帝就像 我喜欢我喜欢 你是 谁
Jesus I want to spend more time with you
耶稣我想花更多的时间和你在一起
and then Jesus sets it straight and he
然后 耶稣把它说得直，他
says unless one is born of water and
除非一个人 出生于水 和 水
here it is and the holy spirit he cannot
这是它和他不能的圣灵
enter into the kingdom of God and true
进入神 的 国度，真实
conversion is a most supernatural thing
转换是一种超自然现象
God isn't looking to keep people out he
上帝不希望让人们离开他
wants people in but he makes it very
我希望有人进入，但他做得很好
clear unless the Holy Spirit comes in
除非圣灵进来，否则要清楚
and makes us brand-new cleansing us of
并使我们全新的清洁我们
all of our sin and God makes it very
我们所有的罪和上帝都是如此
clear I'm sorry no nothing sinful or
清楚我很抱歉 没有任何罪恶 或
unholy is coming anywhere near me or my
不圣洁的人来到我或我的附近
kingdom sorry but we don't have to stay
王国 抱歉，但我们没有留下来
that way
那样
that's right we can call on his name and
这是对的， 我们 可以打电话给他的名字 和
whoever calls on the name of the Lord
无论谁呼唤主 的 名字
will be saved
将 被保存
the Holy Spirit he's our regenerator
圣灵他是我们的再生者
Jeff all right god that's a great spot -
杰夫， 所有的 上帝，这是一个伟大的地方 -
Wow
哇
and we've still got six more traits to
我们还有六个特征
go I can't wait for next week it's gonna
走我不能等待 下周它 会
be good it's gonna be a great series
好，这将是 一个伟大的系列
friends again we commend to you the
朋友们再次向你们表示赞赏
Bible app called you version there's so
圣经 的应用程序称为你的版本 有这么
many good things that many of you are
很多好东西，很多人都是
using it already maybe there's someone a
使用它可能已经有人了
friend who doesn't have it yet we come
没有它的朋友我们来了
in YouVersion Bible app check out the
在YouVersion圣经应用程序检查出来
seven rolls of the Holy Spirit you can
你可以 七卷 圣灵
follow along with us that's right we're
跟随我们， 我们是对的
gonna go in Detroit number two next week
要 下两个星期 去 底特律号
but in the meantime you have a wonderful
但与此同时，你有一个 美好的
week be blessed and we'll see you next
一周祝福，我们接下来会见到你
god bless you
上帝祝福你
catch a new episode of new every day
每天都会看到新的一集
every Friday morning at new every day TV
每个星期五早上每天都有新 电视
we're
我们
so on roku cody flex youtube google play
所以在roku cody flex youtube google play
music podcasts and news book or if
音乐播客和新闻书或如果
you're in Southern California tune in
你在南加州 调到
every Sunday morning at 6:30 on kbdb TV
每周日早上6:30在kbdb电视台播出
channel 33 television for the high
33 频道的电视频道很高
desert
沙漠
[Music]
[音乐]